Because the Qibla is a
direction,
not a point. Please let us,
that's the second rule.
The first rule regarding
answering this question
is that not every deviation
counts as
deviation in terms of the
Qibla.
Some does not count.
It may be deviating,
but it does not count.
It does not count as from the
things that will invalidate
Yusuf.
It does not count to say you
deviated from the Qibla.
You are still within the
range of
the Qibla. That brings us to
the
second basic rule that the
Qibla is
a direction and not a point.
The meaning is that it has a
wide range. If you are an
architect
or an engineering person,
you understand what I mean.
The difference between facing
a point and
facing a direction. There is
a big
difference between
facing a point and facing a
direction.
The Qibla is a direction and
not
a point.
Because Allah says,
فَوَلُّ وُجُوهَكُمْ شَطْرَ
الْمَزْجِدِ الْفَرَامِ
Shatra there means in the
direction of
Masjid al-Haram.
فَوَلُّ وُجُوهَكُمْ
شَطْرَحَمِ
This shatru is direction.
So and then he said in that
hadith of Abu Hurairah that
فَوَلُّ وُجُوهَكُمْ
شَطْرَحَمِ
So between the east and the
west
is the Qibla. It means the
Qibla
is a direction.